# D. CRISTINA TERRY

Alameda, CA 94501

Phone:415-450-8365| Email: crisdc88@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/dcristinaterry | Github: https://github.com/dcristinaterry

Portfolio: https://dcristinaterry.github.io/portfolio/

### **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

Full Stack Web Developer, passionate problem solver with 10+ years of experience in multiple roles within the software development field. Enthusiastic and committed to collaborate with others to identify optimum solutions. Served in roles within different industries ranging from Systems Analyst to Software Engineer using Java as the main coding language. Recently received in-depth training in Full-Stack Web Development applications from UC Berkeley, using frameworks such as Tailwinds CSS and React, and languages such as Node, Javascript and MySql. Previously worked in converting and migrating different types of electronic messaging, with a particular focus on social media messages, which resulted in over \$10,000 USD per migration in revenue to the company.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Languages:** Java, mySql, Node Js, webServices, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, HandleBars, Tailwind CSS, Sequelize, Mongo, mongoose.

Applications: Eclipse, VS Code, mySql Workbench, Jira, Zira.

**Other:** Systems Analysis • Requirements Gathering and Ambiguity Analysis • Project Coordination • Test

Automation.

Fluent in Spanish and English

#### WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Study-Buddy | GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/crisdc88/P3-Study-Budy">https://github.com/crisdc88/P3-Study-Budy</a> Link to Deployed Project :

- Developed an application which provided students with a better means to interact, schedule and host group study sessions.
- Core Responsibilities: System Design, DataBase design, API,React component setup and design, Development back, Front End (react),
- Tools / languages used: HTML CSS JavaScript Tailwind CSS Axios Moment.js DatePicker Node.js Express MySQL Workbench Sequelize React JSX Git GitHub Heroku.

Groceries List | GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/dcristinaterry/GROCERIES-LIST">https://github.com/dcristinaterry/GROCERIES-LIST</a> Link to Deployed Project : <a href="https://ct-groceries-list.herokuapp.com/">https://ct-groceries-list.herokuapp.com/</a>

- Developed an application which allows the user to save a list of items and move them to different places. This allows the user to track the items on every step of the process.
- Core Responsibilities: System Design, DataBase design, Development back and Front End.
- Tools / languages used: HTML CSS JavaScript Bootstrap Node.js Express MySQL Workbench Git GitHub Heroku.

Study-Buddy | GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/dcristinaterry/WEATHER-INFO">https://github.com/dcristinaterry/WEATHER-INFO</a> Link to Deployed Project: <a href="https://dcristinaterry.github.io/WEATHER-INFO/">https://dcristinaterry.github.io/WEATHER-INFO/</a>

- Developed an application which allows the user to check the weather for a City and have a 5 day weathercast
- Core Responsibilities: System Design, DataBase design, Development back and Front End.
- Tools / languages used: HTML CSS JavaScript Bootstrap ¡Query Ajax Git GitHub.

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer MicroFocus (Former HPE)

2017 – 2020 Pleasanton, CA

Implemented and enhanced enterprise software solutions to transform, enrich and migrate large structured datasets.

- Migrated social media data of financial organizations into the Digital Safe Cloud system using Java, Spring, JPA, Hibernate, RESTful web services, Bash, MySQL and SMAP frameworks.
- Migrated PST data into the Digital Safe Cloud system using Visual Studio .net, JPA, Hibernate, RESTful web services, Bash, MySQL and SMAP frameworks.
- Collaborated with project managers, client directors and system engineers from project inception to completion, providing technical expertise and troubleshooting as required.

# **SVC-ITO Service Delivery** MicroFocus (Former HPE)

2014 – 2017 Pleasanton, CA

Analyzed and Implemented an Automation Testing Framework iSTF to build Automated test cases for MicroFocus' applications (Digital Safe and Supervisor) based on client requirements.

- Decreased monitoring time, generation of early alerts and reduced need for manual systems checks for all clients, including but not limited to major organizations such as TD bank, North Western Mutual and Shell.
- Configured the application to meet client requirements.
- Testing and troubleshooting errors and maintaining direct communication with the clients.

Systems Analyst / Product Manager. Bancolombia

2009 - 2013

Medellin, Colombia

Contributed to the development of credit card application solutions with a major focus on integration with legacy software.

- Redesigned internal processes using various technologies including SAP, Sales Force and others.
- Oversaw progress, gathered requirements, created technical designs and other deliverables in alignment with functional requirements for various projects.
- Handled IT support training on all new applications.
- Major achievements included successfully leading the design and development acting as the key expert on the new credit card reward system and compliance report application.

## **EDUCATION**

Bootcamp Certificate: Berkeley University, Berkeley, CA

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Master of Science in Computer Science (Dec 2015): MIU - Fairfield, Iowa

Bachelor of Science in Systems Engineering (2008): EAFIT University – Medellin, Colombia

Professional Development: ITIL v3 Foundation Certification